<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Basic-Citizen-Income on Leon Paternoster </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/categories/basic-citizen-income/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The morality of work</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/06/the-morality-of-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/06/the-morality-of-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the &amp;#8220;morality of work&amp;#8221;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the idea that people essentially have a duty to work, an inherent need to work, that work is an instrument to achieving things like self&amp;#8211;esteem and social cohesion. Obviously, this is sort of true. What really matters here is how you define Work. What gets thought of as Work and what is &amp;#8220;not work&amp;#8221; becomes a real bone of contention. In our current society, care work – whether for children, siblings, relatives, friends, strangers – is not considered Work. Housework is not considered Work. Study is not Work. Charity is not Work. Social work is not Work. But all these things are inherent in social cohesion, they are just not valued particularly highly as far as financial reward goes. &amp;#8212;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irishleftreview.org/2014/06/11/basic-income-summer-forum/&#34;&gt;Basic Income Summer Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is only partly right. If we&amp;#8217;re being honest, most people &amp;#8211; apart from politicians when they&amp;#8217;re arguing for things like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boycottworkfare.org/&#34;&gt;workfare&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; don&amp;#8217;t see work in such romantic terms. It&amp;#8217;s not a route to self&amp;#8211;esteem, social cohesion etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work for most people is above all else &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;, something that has to be done in order to pay the bills. Antipathy to Basic Income (or any form of benefit) comes from the view that because &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; have to work hard to buy food and pay the gas bill, &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; shouldn&amp;#8217;t get free money from me. &lt;em&gt;That&amp;#8217;s&lt;/em&gt; the morality of work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 right wing reasons for a Basic Citizens&#39; Income</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/10/3-neoliberal-reasons-for-basic-income/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/10/3-neoliberal-reasons-for-basic-income/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A Basic Citizens&amp;#8217; Income (BCI) is one of those subjects that&amp;#8217;s fun to think about (if you&amp;#8217;re philosophically or politically inclined – I guess other people find it mortally dull, for which I apologise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It serves as a thought experiment – what if the role of the state wasn&amp;#8217;t to punish poverty? – which can lead down some surprising alleyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example &lt;em&gt;what is the right&amp;#8217;s attitude to BCI&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your instinct says &lt;em&gt;the right will absolutely hate&lt;/em&gt; a BCI, and you probably wouldn&amp;#8217;t be mistaken. It doesn&amp;#8217;t exactly fit in with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-24327470&#34;&gt;Gideon&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;something for nothing culture&lt;/em&gt; rhetoric&lt;/a&gt;, and its main UK proponents are various leftwingers and the Green Party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;#8217;s no inherent reason for the right to adopt a punitive attitude to welfare. If the starting point of any welfare system is &lt;em&gt;how do we encourage entrpreneuralism&lt;/em&gt;? (how I hate that word) or &lt;em&gt;how do we minimise state bureacracy&lt;/em&gt;?, or even &lt;em&gt;how do we encourage people to work&lt;/em&gt;? then BCI becomes a lot more attractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course – as I always point out – this will not happen, because the starting point of all social policy is &lt;em&gt;how do we punish poverty&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;figure class=&#34;figure alignnone&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-64&#34; alt=&#34;Two women sitting at a table in a cafe&#34; src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/newsnight.jpg&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;301&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;BBC Newsnight political editor Allegra Stratton &lt;a href=&#34;http://politicalscrapbook.net/2012/06/newsnight-allegra-stratton-exposed-shanene-thorpe/&#34;&gt;falsely portrayed Shanene Thorpe as a “jobless ponce”&lt;/a&gt;. Her prejudice is widespread – even at the supposedly objective BBC.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
But here are 3 reasons for the right to embrace BCI:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;1. It encourages entrepreneurs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current benefits system deters people from working piecemeal. As soon as you work one single hour, you lose benefits. This means that it&amp;#8217;s only worth working if you can work lots of hours on a regular, predictable basis. Working now and again is not only financially pointless, it means you have to deal with the nightmare bureaucracy of the DWP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s say you&amp;#8217;ve worked for a couple of years as a ‘junior’ web developer. You&amp;#8217;ve kept up to date with all the latest trends in your field and know you could do a better job than the company that just made you redundant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A BCI would encourage you to take a risk. You could set yourself up as a self–employed developer and starting bidding for work. You wouldn&amp;#8217;t have to rely on being able to secure credit, or a rich mum and dad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your business failed you&amp;#8217;d have your BCI to fall back on. If it was slow to take off – building a reputation is difficult – and only earned a couple of hundred quid a month you&amp;#8217;d still keep that income and pay tax on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows – over time you might become a really successful business woman, while the economy gains a high quality web developer. You might start employing people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;2. It rids us of state bureaucracy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current income support and tax credits system is a Kafkaesque bureaucracy of different rates, forms, ages, sanctions and administrators (although this does create employment, ironically enough. Imagine if there were no poor people to keep tabs on and sanction – no poverty industry.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; receives BCI regardless of age, marital status, income and employment status, there&amp;#8217;s nothing to process except a weekly or monthly payment. No signing on, back to work schemes or changes in circumstances forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the UK, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citizensincome.org/filelibrary/Archived%20Publications/Citizen%27s%20Income%20booklet%202013.doc&#34;&gt;BCI would save £7 billion per year in tax credits and income support administration costs&lt;/a&gt; (Word doc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;3. It makes it easier to liberalise employment laws and create a ‘free’ market&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right argues minimum hour contracts, a minimum wage and redundancy protection rights ‘stifle’ business growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While far more ‘protective’ countries than the UK seem to manage perfectly well (Germany, most obviously), other traditionally &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denmark#Public_policy&#34;&gt;social democratic countries such as Denmark have adopted an even more neoliberal approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the UK, Denmark has extremely high unemployment benefit levels. In effect, there&amp;#8217;s a contract between the state, workers and employers. Employers can hire and fire at will, but workers don&amp;#8217;t face ruinous consequences if they lose their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the UK there&amp;#8217;s no such contract, which makes employment law liberalisation extremely unfair and dangerous to workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BCI could form part of a contract between workers and employers. It would allow employers to hire and fire more freely, while giving workers a basic level of security. The government could abolish the minimum wage, meaning market forces would determine pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BCI appeals to a strain of anarchism common to neoliberal and leftwing thought. It&amp;#8217;s a shame such a rational, practical idea that works across ideologies doesn&amp;#8217;t have a chance in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*[DWP]: Department of Work And Pensions&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low expectations</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/10/swiss-basic-income-low-uk-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/10/swiss-basic-income-low-uk-expectations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switzerland will hold a vote on whether to introduce a basic income for all adults, in a further sign of growing public activism over pay inequality since the financial crisis. A grassroots committee is calling for all adults in Switzerland to receive an unconditional income of 2,500 Swiss francs (2,800 USD) per month from the state, with the aim of providing a financial safety net for the population. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/10/04/us-swiss-pay-idUSBRE9930O620131004&#34;&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt; via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/basicincome_uk&#34;&gt;Basic Income UK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you&amp;#8217;re no doubt very bored of hearing, I&amp;#8217;m interested in the idea of a Basic Citizen Income: a non–withdrawable, non–means tested income for every UK citizen, regardless of employment status, age and marital status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I blogged &lt;a href=&#34;/2013/09/basic-income-examples/&#34;&gt;a couple of examples of how it might work in the UK&lt;/a&gt;, using figures published by Dr Malcolm Torry. Unfortunately, it&amp;#8217;ll never happen, due to our punitive attitude to poor people.&lt;figure class=&#34;figure alignnone&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-59&#34; alt=&#34;Some people sweeping coins outside the Swiss parliament&#34; src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/swiss-money.jpg&#34; width=&#34;634&#34; height=&#34;421&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;Swiss Generation Basic Income activists outside their parliament&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
What&amp;#8217;s interesting about the Swiss proposal is the amount they&amp;#8217;ll be voting on. In the UK 2800 USD amounts to about £1750, i.e. the average full–time worker&amp;#8217;s net pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my examples, anyone over the age of 24 would receive £308 a month, &lt;em&gt;around £1400 less than in Switzerland&lt;/em&gt;. And yet it still seems a million miles away. (Note: Dr Torry&amp;#8217;s figures assume housing and council tax benefits remain the same. They substantially increase UK state derived income.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this say about UK expectations of pay and quality of life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*[USD]: US dollars&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic citizen income—two examples of how it would work</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/09/basic-income-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/09/basic-income-examples/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Now, we all know a basic citizen income will never happen in the UK, because of &lt;a href=&#34;/2013/09/basic-income/&#34;&gt;our punitive attitude to benefits&lt;/a&gt;. However, it&amp;#8217;s interesting to look at how it would affect us &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; we actually created a system that supported people regardless of their circumstances. We can but dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following scenarios and figures are based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citizensincome.org/MoneyforEveryone.htm&#34;&gt;Dr Malcolm Torry&amp;#8217;s work for the Citizen&amp;#8217;s Income Trust&lt;/a&gt; (see Appendix 16). He claims the proposals are revenue neutral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state would give every citizen a fixed income regardless of their salary, pension, investment income, age and marital status. Dr Torry proposes income levels based on current income support and pension credit rates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&#34;pure-table&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Age
    &lt;/th&gt;
    
    &lt;th&gt;
      Weekly rate
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      0–15
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      £56.25
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      16–24
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      £56.25
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      25–64
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      £71.00
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      65+
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      £142.70
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;
  Weekly basic citizen income amounts
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Example 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A and B are married and have two school aged children. A earns the national average wage of £26,500 a year. B hasn&amp;#8217;t worked for four years in order to bring up the children. B would like to find a part–time job or course in order to begin a return to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family collects £160 a month in child tax credits and £134 child benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After tax and national insurance (NI) A takes home £1700 a month. This results in a total income of £1994 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment it&amp;#8217;s next to impossible for B to find work or study, because they&amp;#8217;ll lose their tax credits and have to start paying for pre and after school childcare, and any course costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under a basic citizen income scheme A would pay more income tax because there&amp;#8217;d be no tax allowance. Using the current tax rates, tax and NI add up to 32%, so A would take home £1502 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic income is paid to all citizens regardless of age. Using Torry&amp;#8217;s suggested rates, the family would receive £1103 citizen income a month. This results in a total income of £2605 a month, £611 more than the current amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;How things would change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B could look for work without worrying about losing child tax credits. If the government also subsidised free childcare, it would be even more attractive. Study would be a realistic option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also several indirect benefits. A currently pays £60 accident, sickness and unemployment insurance. They wouldn&amp;#8217;t need to pay as much because redundancy wouldn&amp;#8217;t be as ruinous as before (moving to part–time work would be a realistic option, for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A could change their work hours to share childcare duties. It might be possible to go part–time in order to improve B&amp;#8217;s job and study prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A citizen income would drastically improve financial security, work and study flexibility and the quality of A and B&amp;#8217;s life (and their children&amp;#8217;s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Example 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C brings up three children on their own. Their youngest child has turned 5, which means they have to move to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/employment-support-allowance/what-youll-get&#34;&gt;Employment and Support Allowance (ESA)&lt;/a&gt; benefit of £71.70 a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 13 weeks they&amp;#8217;ll be put into a sinisterly named “work related activity group” and face sanctions if they don&amp;#8217;t attend job interviews or do “work–related activity”. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adviceguide.org.uk/wales/benefits_w/benefits_sick_or_disabled_people_and_carers_ew/employment_and_support_allowance.htm#work-related_activity&#34;&gt;Work related activity&lt;/a&gt; is work for free (also known as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boycottworkfare.org/&#34;&gt;workfare&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They currently claim £376.11 a month child tax credits and £204.10 child benefit. Total income is £890.91 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C would like to either work part–time or, because they have no formal qualifications, begin an access course so they can train for a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C would lose their ESA under the current rules if they started a course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the basic citizen income scheme, the family&amp;#8217;s income would increase by a modest £148 a month to £1038.91. C wouldn&amp;#8217;t have to start unpaid “work–related activity”, and they&amp;#8217;d be free to either study or work part–time without losing any money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;How things would change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C wouldn&amp;#8217;t have to worry about a change in circumstances affecting their children&amp;#8217;s well–being. They could also concentrate on planning some sort of career, rather than how their income changes on a week to week basis, or working for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common theme to these examples is education. Another indirect consequence of a basic income would be a better trained workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Why it won&amp;#8217;t happen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Torry&amp;#8217;s cost neutral claims are true, then it&amp;#8217;s hard to argue against a basic citizen income. They serve the government&amp;#8217;s aim of &lt;em&gt;getting people back to work&lt;/em&gt; far better than the current means tested system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re of a neoliberal bent they also open up several interesting possibilities around ‘flexible’ labour laws. If unemployment isn&amp;#8217;t entirely financially ruinous, then zero hour contracts and no quibble hiring and firing may seem a little fairer than they do at the moment. (&lt;em&gt;Note – this isn&amp;#8217;t my view!&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the main drawback is that an untested citizen income isn&amp;#8217;t punitive. In real life, A is encouraged to feel that they&amp;#8217;re paying for C to ‘do nothing’ while they struggle on a low income, instead of questioning why their salary is so inadequate. Benefits and work are an exercise in division and revenge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic citizen income—genius idea the UK will never adopt</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/09/basic-income/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/09/basic-income/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our conclusion has to be that every mainstream political ideology generates arguments for a citizen&amp;#8217;s income. Arguments against are more generic, and are not generated by political ideologies themselves, and are easily answered. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.lse.ac.uk/politicsandpolicy/archives/34269&#34;&gt;There are many convincing arguments in favour of a Citizen’s Income&lt;/a&gt;—Dr Malcolm Torry&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very true. Imagine implementing a policy that made work a rational choice for everybody, regardless of their income, status or age, rid unemployment of its ruinous consequences, improved the psychical health of the nation, allowed people to work around their family life and put an end to the vilification of the unemployed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re neoliberally inclined, your arguments for repealing employment protection laws would at least seem fairer (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denmark#Public_policy&#34;&gt;a la Denmark&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;d also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/celebritynews/10266648/Jamie-Oliver-sparks-poverty-row-after-he-attacks-families-for-eating-junk-food-and-buying-expensive-TV-sets.html&#34;&gt;shut Jamie Oliver up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet it&amp;#8217;ll never happen in the UK, because ideology (mainstream or otherwise) and our attitude to work aren&amp;#8217;t rational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the British attitude to work, benefits and reward? There&amp;#8217;s an element of masochism (that positively enjoys working in unfair circumstances), offset by a vengeful moralism (the division of the fellow fucked–over poor into deserving and undeserving categories) and a morbid fascination with property as a moral reward for this suffering – even though owning a house has very little to do with hard work. All irrational, illiberal and self defeating, and totally at odds with an unconditional basic income.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>