<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Website-Management on Leon Paternoster </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/categories/website-management/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 ways to use in site search data to improve your website</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/05/5-ways-to-use-in-site-search-data-to-improve-your-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/05/5-ways-to-use-in-site-search-data-to-improve-your-website/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Keep your users&amp;#8217; website search queries within easy reach to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See what’s important to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn their language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And know how your search engine works to make improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 ways I use in site search data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;1. Add search data to your CMS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty easy to set up Google Analytics (GA) to track what your customers search for on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s better when you have search data to hand. If you’re managing a website you’ll be spending most your day–to–day time in your Content Management System (CMS), so that’s where you should be able to find search data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&#34;http://suffolklibraries.co.uk&#34;&gt;Suffolk Libraries&lt;/a&gt; website I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.relevanssi.com/&#34;&gt;Relevanssi&lt;/a&gt;, which displays user queries in the WordPress dashboard.&lt;figure class=&#34;figure alignnone&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/search-screenshot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Relevanssi search queries&#34; width=&#34;760&#34; height=&#34;599&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;The Relevanssi user searches page&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
I look at search queries whenever I have a couple of minutes spare, so I can make and test little copy and structural changes all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;2. Use search terms to write pages and structure your site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If users are searching for the same thing over and over again it could indicate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re missing some important content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customers can’t find important content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or, more simply, what users come to your website to look for (remember: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/search-navigation/&#34;&gt;many visitors head straight for your search box&lt;/a&gt; and don’t bother too much with navigation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever it indicates you might need to take action. Think about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;writing new content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rewriting existing content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making important content easier to find (perhaps by providing a shortcut on your home page, or by restructuring/streamlining your existing navigation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;3. Learn your users’ language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organisations use different words from users to describe the service they offer. Whether the organisational lingo is ‘better ’ than the user’s doesn’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may refer to &lt;em&gt;titles&lt;/em&gt; because the library offers books, films, epubs, CDs, DVDs, streaming and MP3s and it’s a convenient umbrella term. However, when users come to your website they often (but not always) have a particular format in mind. They want to borrow a book, so they search for something like &lt;em&gt;how do I borrow a book online&lt;/em&gt;. So your pages have to contain the terms &lt;em&gt;borrow&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;book&lt;/em&gt; (or you need to work on synonyms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll see this analysis doesn’t just apply to how you label services. It can get quite complex when users think about processes, such as borrowing and renewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;4. Know how your search engine works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve identified a problem and written some content you’re nearly there. The final piece of the jigsaw is understanding how your search engine will find that content and display it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to think about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What types of content the engine searches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the engine does relevancy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can it handle synonyms?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Content types&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relevanssi allows you to omit or weight certain post types and comments from search results. So you can stop comments appearing in results, or make sure the engine favours pages over comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any one time we have several thousand events published on the website (which is probably a problem in and of itself). We’ve therefore taken the decision to exclude events from search results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Relevancy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decent search engine attempts to sort search results by how relevant they are to the searcher. The simplest mechanism to control relevancy is through field (title, content, excerpt etc.) weighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, you can assign each WordPress post field a score which Relevanssi uses to calculate how relevant the post is. You can use this to make the title field a lot more important than, say, the excerpt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’ve weighted fields you can make sure titles contain common user search words and terms so they appear among the first results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Synonyms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We often label &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt; with different words, which may have slightly different meanings. Words drop out of popular usage over time, so what’s now a &lt;em&gt;bucket&lt;/em&gt; was once, more or less, a &lt;em&gt;pail&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engines let you group several words under one meaning. So I could make &lt;em&gt;book&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt; mean the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt;. I haven’t really used this Relevanssi feature as language usage is so unpredictable. What if someone really wanted to search for something to do with the titles of books rather than books? What if you use &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt; to mean title rather than &lt;em&gt;book&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;5. Test your search set up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search can be a complex beast, especially if you&amp;#8217;ve got lots of options to tweak (which is why using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/cse/&#34;&gt;Google Custom Search Engine&lt;/a&gt; often appeals).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re making extensive or complex changes, test them out on your staging site first, and keep an eye on your search logs and analytics once you&amp;#8217;ve made them live.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 things to do with a website content audit</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/04/3-things-to-do-with-a-website-content-audit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/04/3-things-to-do-with-a-website-content-audit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A year or so ago I posted &lt;a href=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/2013/04/carrying-out-a-web-content-audit/&#34; title=&#34;Carrying out a web content audit&#34;&gt;a guide to carrying out a content audit&lt;/a&gt;. At the time I was getting to grips with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://suffolklibraries.co.uk&#34;&gt;Suffolk Libraries&lt;/a&gt; website, and the audit was a really useful way to understand the library service and what we were trying to do online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a (hopefully) sane IA and most of the redundant content has been stripped away, the audit has a different purpose. I use it to prune pages and make sure everything&amp;#8217;s up to date. The original audit took days, now it takes on hour or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are 3 things you can do with a content audit once you&amp;#8217;re happy with your website&amp;#8217;s structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;1. Make sure content is assigned to the right owner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staff move on, go on paternity leave or get promoted. Your organisation structure changes too. Update your content owners accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;2. Delete pages and files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Suffolk Libraries website consists of 144 static pages, including redirects. This is manageable for one person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fewer pages and files make it easier to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;structure your website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;return relevant results from searches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;navigate pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first question you need to ask of any page or file is &lt;em&gt;do we need this?* If you think the answer&amp;#8217;s *no&lt;/em&gt;, check your analytics and search logs and ask the content owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;3. Update content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll probably have an idea of what content needs updating, but the audit will &lt;em&gt;force&lt;/em&gt; you to review everything. It&amp;#8217;ll throw light on those obscure corners of the website you&amp;#8217;d forgotten about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information ages quite naturally, but sometimes something unpredictable happens. For example, a new government might make changes to the National Curriculum, so your children&amp;#8217;s reading advice pages might need updating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often content owners will come to you with changes, but it&amp;#8217;s ultimately your responsibility to make sure everything&amp;#8217;s up to date. And it&amp;#8217;s a good thing when you show enough interest in other people&amp;#8217;s content to ask questions about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first content audit I did for Suffolk Libraries was a major piece of work, but it was really important to get a handle on the website. Now it&amp;#8217;s a relatively painless way to keep the site lean and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*[IA]: Information Architecture&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your website is not as important as your catalogue</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/05/your-website-is-not-as-important-as-your-catalogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/05/your-website-is-not-as-important-as-your-catalogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your website is not as important as your catalog. This is a fact. We’ve asked many nonlibrarians about what they do on library websites, and the usual response is “Place reserves on books.” This is subtly different from how we think of our websites and catalogs (i.e., as distinct things). So, either our users see the two as the same thing, or they ignore our websites and just use our catalogs. Looking at website analytics suggests the latter. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/doc/91222042/User-Experience-and-Library-Websites&#34;&gt;User Experience (UX) Design for Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your commonsense, analytics and visitor research will all point to this fundamental truth. And it&amp;#8217;s an awkward truth, because chances are &lt;a href=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/2013/04/library-websites-catalogues-and-their-poor-ux/&#34;&gt;you have virtually no control over the public face of your catalogue&lt;/a&gt;. You probably didn&amp;#8217;t even have a say in what catalogue your library chose, because that&amp;#8217;s the concern of the stock unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s also difficult to change. The people you work with are probably responsible for all sorts of things in your library that can be done online: marketing, writing news, arranging events, running friends groups, setting up a reading group, setting up reference services. Anything but sorting out the search for the public—unless they deal with a member of that public who hasn&amp;#8217;t been able to find a not particularly esoteric text on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrying out a web content audit</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/04/carrying-out-a-web-content-audit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/04/carrying-out-a-web-content-audit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been undertaking a couple of largish projects since starting work as &lt;a href=&#34;http://suffolklibraries.co.uk&#34;&gt;Suffolk Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216; web manager. The first is a content audit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s worth auditing your existing web content whether you think a big redesign is in order or not. Of course, there&amp;#8217;s rarely a time when a new web manager starts their job without thinking the site needs some improvement, but even if you&amp;#8217;ve decided on an evolution not revolution approach, an audit still serves as a starting point for your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll refer you to &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.web-content-strategy.com/&#34;&gt;The Content Strategist&amp;#8217;s Bible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt; at this point. It goes into this stuff in great detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What is a content audit?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A content audit is a list (normally a spreadsheet) of all the things your organisation publishes online. In practice this mostly means the content you publish on your website, including the HTML pages, images and assets like PDFs. There are always lots of PDFs to discover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve listed everything you assign each item an owner. The owner isn&amp;#8217;t the person who edits, creates or deletes content; it&amp;#8217;s whoever is responsible for providing the content. So while I might write the page for Ipswich County Library, it&amp;#8217;s the library manager who is responsible for providing the details, such as contact number and regular events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll also add other details to each content item, depending on the size of the site and your team. If your CMS doesn&amp;#8217;t have a review date feature, you could start adding dates here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audit is useful for lots of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives you an insight into what your organisation does and who&amp;#8217;s responsible for what.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No matter how dire a website&amp;#8217;s navigation and design seem, it&amp;#8217;ll still contain content the public finds useful. An audit will reveal this important content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You get a ‘big picture’ of the website. This will give you some immediate ideas for improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives you someone to go to when you want to change content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You know who to ask when you want to remove content. Getting agreement when you want to make big changes makes your job a lot easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It reveals obvious problems in the site&amp;#8217;s IA that can be corrected quite quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes the job of updating and managing content a lot easier. Once you&amp;#8217;ve listed all your content you can easily schedule content reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve got a handle on your existing content it&amp;#8217;s a lot easier to migrate it to a different platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a major part of your top task research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Carrying out the audit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suprisingly enough, content management systems (CMSs) don&amp;#8217;t perform basic content management functions particularly well. For example, it&amp;#8217;d be handy if your CMS could output a list of every page on your website, and make it available for export to a spreadsheet. Many CMSs don&amp;#8217;t even have a review date feature, let alone a page owner field for each piece of content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way round this is to hunt out your site&amp;#8217;s &lt;code&gt;sitemap.xml&lt;/code&gt; file, assuming it has one. This will normally live at &lt;code&gt;yoursite.com/sitemap.xml&lt;/code&gt;. If you don&amp;#8217;t have a sitemap you&amp;#8217;re going to be doing a lot of clicking and listing pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sitemap will list every page on your site. Converting it to a spreadsheet is simple (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.luxonsoftware.com/converter/xmltoexcel&#34;&gt;I uploaded it to an online XML to Excel converter&lt;/a&gt;). Getting a list of assets is a bit more difficult—you might have to add them manually by searching through the CMS. Failing that, you can perform a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/cse/sitesearch/create&#34;&gt;Google site search&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;code&gt;*.pdf&lt;/code&gt; and other relevant extensions. Like I say, this will reveal all sorts of goodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve got your list you&amp;#8217;ll have to go through each item and assign it an owner. You might add a comments column and, depending on the size of the site and your team, information such as item editor. It&amp;#8217;s also useful to record the content&amp;#8217;s format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most sites publish lots of repetitive content such as events and news entries. If the owner is the same for all of these items, there&amp;#8217;s no need to list every single one. Just include an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comments you add at this stage are important. It&amp;#8217;s here you&amp;#8217;ll think about the content&amp;#8217;s value, its label and its place within the site structure. At this point you&amp;#8217;re in an interesting situation as you&amp;#8217;re looking at the website with an outsider&amp;#8217;s eyes, just as a customer might.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;What to do with the audit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audit is a goldmine. I found it reveals IA problems that are quite easy to fix straight away. Tell the relevant content owner(s) what you plan to do, get their agreement and go ahead and do it. This is a good time to establish some content editing/creation/deletion processes with the organisation as a whole and any other content editors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you&amp;#8217;re at it, you can identify redundant content and start deleting it. You don&amp;#8217;t need to publish events that took place two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will keep you occupied during the first few weeks of your job. Once you&amp;#8217;ve completed the audit you can use it to start another big piece of work—top task research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library websites, catalogues and their poor UX</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/04/library-websites-catalogues-and-their-poor-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/04/library-websites-catalogues-and-their-poor-ux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started working for &lt;a href=&#34;http://suffolklibraries.co.uk&#34;&gt;Suffolk Libraries&lt;/a&gt; last week. Over the next few months I&amp;#8217;ll be rebuilding our website. If you take a look now, you&amp;#8217;ll see why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libraries and the internet seem to share an uncomfortable relationship. I can see a few reasons for this. The main one is that Online Public Access Catalogues (OPACs) are not designed to slot into existing websites. They live as separate entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s why you&amp;#8217;re shunted off to a subdomain or even a different website whenever you search for a title, whichever library website you try:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://librarycatalogue.manchester.gov.uk&#34;&gt;Manchester Central Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://library-opac.birmingham.gov.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/MSGTRN/OPAC/HOME&#34;&gt;Birmingham Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nypl.bibliocommons.com/&#34;&gt;New York Public Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This strikes me as exceptionally poor UX. If I go to find a book on a library website I expect to be able to find it on that site. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/top-10-ia-mistakes/&#34;&gt;Navigating across websites is confusing&lt;/a&gt;. And isn&amp;#8217;t a library essentially a collection of texts? Why aren&amp;#8217;t they actually housed in the library?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libraries have tackled this problem in two ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some attempt to make the OPAC seem a part of the main site. This is what we&amp;#8217;ve done in the past, and it&amp;#8217;s my least favourite option. The pages are styled in the same way as the rest of the website, and the navigation is replicated. This strikes me as fundamentally &lt;em&gt;dishonest&lt;/em&gt;. It also makes it a PITA to make simple changes to the website IA, especially when your OPAC isn&amp;#8217;t a CMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others apply some light branding to the subdomain, perhaps through adding a logo. I prefer this approach as it doesn&amp;#8217;t try and hide what&amp;#8217;s happening to the user. But hopping between websites is a confusing experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world users would tap in their query and the website would display a list of search results. You&amp;#8217;d expect this to be easy enough to implement even if the website itself didn&amp;#8217;t store the database records. That&amp;#8217;s what APIs are for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here we run into a second problem. Suffolk Libraries is unique in that it is a completely separate entity from its council. But its OPAC still feels like something from the world of local government – it looks dated and is difficult to talk to. If you were able to come up with a library management system with an easy, open API you&amp;#8217;d make a killing (there&amp;#8217;s a business idea for you.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that providing services across disparate domains and services has become a habit. That&amp;#8217;s why you&amp;#8217;ll see yet more subsites popping up, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://manchesterdownload.lib.overdrive.com/&#34;&gt;ebook provider Overdrive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect this will pose the main challenge in my website redesign. Is there anyone out there with experience of dealing with OPACs? I guess screen scraping is an option. Or is there actually a way to do subdomains and separate websites well?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>