<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Design on Leon Paternoster </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/design/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabbed navigation didn&#39;t work on our site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/07/tabbed-navigation-didnt-work-on-our-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/07/tabbed-navigation-didnt-work-on-our-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://foundation.zurb.com/docs/components/tabs.html&#34;&gt;tabbed navigation&lt;/a&gt; on a couple of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://suffolklibraries.co.uk&#34;&gt;Suffolk Libraries&lt;/a&gt; website pages. By tabbed navigation I mean a single document&amp;#8217;s content divided by horizontal tabs, so you don&amp;#8217;t see it all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;ll look something like this:&lt;figure class=&#34;figure aligncenter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/tabs.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Tabbed navigation within a page&#34; width=&#34;860&#34; height=&#34;216&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;Tabbed navigation used to break up a single document.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
Tabs might seem a good idea because they break content up, thereby making it easier to interpret. But it&amp;#8217;s the single design element that got the most complaints after my redesign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not that users didn&amp;#8217;t get how to use the tabs (although initial testing indicated the labels had to be clearly styled as links – in the picture above, users might have struggled identifying the tabs). No, it was simply because &lt;strong&gt;tabs can break the back button&lt;/strong&gt;. Users see each tab as a separate page, when in reality they&amp;#8217;re just parts of the same, single page. Although it might seem boring, I found in most cases it makes users&amp;#8217; lives a lot easier if you actually make each tab a separate page, or plump for a single, long document, and find other ways to present it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Observer design not for us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/07/design-observer-design-not-for-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/07/design-observer-design-not-for-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;History repeats itself quickly in the world of web design – it seems like only yesterday &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fawny.org/2009/08/12/mock-do-1/&#34;&gt;we were lambasting &lt;cite&gt;Design Observer&lt;/cite&gt; for its new–not–at–all–new design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 2014 and we&amp;#8217;re making the &lt;a href=&#34;http://typographica.org/on-typography/questions-for-the-new-design-observer/&#34;&gt;same criticisms&lt;/a&gt;: poor font choice, tiny, indistinct type, bugginess. Add some really slow loading and unresponsiveness and you have 2014&amp;#8242;s version (although to be fair the site sort of adjusts to my Nexus phone – I&amp;#8217;m guessing it sniffs rather than scales).&lt;figure class=&#34;figure aligncenter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://designobserver.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;full-bleed&#34; src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/do.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the Design Observer website&#34; width=&#34;860&#34; height=&#34;444&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Design Observer&lt;/cite&gt;: Let me count the ways&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
And yet. This website wasn&amp;#8217;t really written for me. I&amp;#8217;d go as far as to say I don&amp;#8217;t even understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who exactly is it for? Older design veterans who don&amp;#8217;t deal in the grubby functionality of fluid sized screens (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.layervault.com/comments/78785&#34;&gt;designers who aren&amp;#8217;t working class&lt;/a&gt;)? If that is the case then – actual crapness (the huge fixed header, the strange dropdown at the top of the screen etc.) aside – it may do its job well enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you dig seeing paragraphs set in Archer on screen, and like small blocks of text, and spend your day on a Mac with a large screen, &lt;cite&gt;Design Observer&lt;/cite&gt; has been &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; just for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem with cookie banners</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/03/the-problem-with-cookie-banners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/03/the-problem-with-cookie-banners/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Following &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bensmithuk/status/450025400799076353&#34;&gt;Ben’s tweet about CNET’s less than unobtrusive cookie opt–in popup&lt;/a&gt;, I got thinking about these messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re now so common you probably don’t even notice them, even when they take up 112px of your laptop screen:&lt;figure class=&#34;figure alignnone&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Screenshot of the BBC football website with a cookie banner at the top&#34; src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/cookie-message.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;403&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;The BBC Football website&amp;#8217;s big cookie banner. How many people ignore it and just carry on browsing?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;4 reasons cookie banners are useless&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless you’re putting 3rd party ads on your site, you don’t need them
:   In June 2012 the EU data protection authorities adopted an “opinion” that:
:   &amp;gt; First party analytics cookies are not likely to create a privacy risk if websites provide clear information about the cookies to users and privacy safeguards, eg a user friendly mechanism to opt out from any data collection and where they ensure that identifiable information is anonymised. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ico.org.uk/for_organisations/privacy_and_electronic_communications/the_guide/cookies&#34;&gt;ICO Cookie Guidance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
:   In other words, if you’re using Google Analytics to collect data about your own website, you’re fine. You can’t tell &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; is using your website through analytics, and “clear” doesn’t mean “big banner on every page”. We interpreted it as an entry in the help menu and &lt;a href=&#34;http://suffolklibraries.co.uk/help/privacy-and-cookies/&#34;&gt;a plainly written explanation of what information we collect and what we use it for&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They’re a pain
:   They get in the way. They make your visitors read something, interpret it and then make a decision, when all they wanted to do was read the news.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you just ignore them
:   We associate banners with advertising, and over the years we’ve learned to filter them out. If a cookie banner does catch our attention, it always says exactly the same thing – another reason not to bother reading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;They use marketese
:   You see, we’re not putting this cookie on your computer so we can track which pages you visit, tell what device you’re using and figure out where you came to our website from. Oh no, it’s to &lt;em&gt;improve your experience&lt;/em&gt;.
:   Of course, we may well use all this information to improve your experience of our website. But that’s not what the cookies themselves do. And we could use all that information for a host of other purposes.
:   If there’s one area where we need to write plainly it’s privacy. &lt;a href=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/2014/02/mozilla-is-selling-ads-although-its-coy-about-telling-us/&#34; title=&#34;Mozilla is selling ads, although it’s coy about telling us&#34;&gt;Talk of user experience is often a smokescreen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;A bodged law&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is wrong for us to put files on our website visitors’ computers without their explicit permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The law should have made it illegal to set cookies without visitors opting in. Instead, we’re allowed to assume they’re OK with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if we had a proper law no–one would bother opting in, and a big bit of the internet would break.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive versus works in IE6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/03/responsive-versus-works-in-ie6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/03/responsive-versus-works-in-ie6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stats from 4 days’ worth of &lt;a href=&#34;http://suffolklibraries.co.uk&#34;&gt;Suffolk Libraries&lt;/a&gt; website traffic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proportion of visits from mobiles and tablets: 1 in 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proportion of visits using Internet Explorer 6: 1 in 500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Suffolk Libraries website is responsive. Cost to build: £0 – I did it, so I guess there’s my web manager salary, but I do all the other web stuff too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at another library service’s website (or, more specifically, another library’s website): &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.libraryofbirmingham.com/&#34;&gt;The Library of Birmingham&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-birmingham-25033651&#34;&gt;Cost to build £1.2m&lt;/a&gt;. Annual running costs £190,000. I don’t earn £190,000 a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing isn’t always cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Library of Birmingham’s website isn’t responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does, however, work in Internet Explorer 6. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.whatdotheyknow.com/request/179465/response/452527/attach/html/3/FOI%209309%20Parry%20Final%20response%20Attach%201.doc.html&#34;&gt;They did ask for it to work in IE6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is the most accessible?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tschichold, democratic design and the politics of typefaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/tschichold-democratic-design-and-the-politics-of-typefaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/tschichold-democratic-design-and-the-politics-of-typefaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Penguin founder Allen Lane hired Jan Tschichold to design the publisher’s book covers in 1947. Tschichold made an immediate impact:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…nothing compared to storm when Jan Tschichold arrived. Mild-mannered man with an inflexible character. Screams heard from Edinburgh to Ipswich and from Aylesbury to Bungay.” This was the result of Tschichold’s immediate effort to raise the standard of undisciplined English typesetting; to his frustration, Tschichold found himself obliged to treat the compositor not as a craftsman but as a machine, by specifying precise measurements for the spaces between each combination of letters in a title. It was the only way to get the results he desired. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/artanddesign/2008/dec/05/jan-tschichold-typography&#34;&gt;Jan Tschichold: a titan of typography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it; the Ipswich Jan Tschichold link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this is an example of what iA refer to as &lt;em&gt;Fingerspitzengefühl&lt;/em&gt;; the fine knowledge of detail that helps produce good design. (Go ahead and read &lt;a href=&#34;http://informationarchitects.net/blog/learning-to-see/&#34;&gt;Learning to See&lt;/a&gt;—you won’t be disappointed.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about design it’s very easy to adopt a reverential, exclusive tone. Design can be used as a means to up the price of a product. But it’s worth bearing in mind that many of the things we think of as examples of great design serve a democratic purpose. Tschischold invented a template for cheap, massproduced books that sold millions of copies:&lt;figure class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;full-bleed alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/penguin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Penguin Great Gatsby cover&#34; width=&#34;616&#34; height=&#34;887&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;Tschichold&amp;#8217;s Penguin book covers, used for millions of cheaply available classics. There&amp;#8217;s no reason why the best design can&amp;#8217;t be commonplace, but it&amp;#8217;s become more and more commoditised in recent years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
Tschischold is an interesting man. He escaped the Nazis in 1933 having published &lt;cite lang=&#34;de&#34;&gt;Die neue Typographie&lt;/cite&gt;, where he claimed sans serifs were the “basic form from which the typeface of the future will grow”. By 1952 he’d performed a &lt;em&gt;volte face&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sanserif only seems to be the simpler script. It is a form that was violently reduced for little children. For adults it is more difficult to read than serifed roman type, whose serifs were never meant to be ornamental. &lt;cite&gt;On Typography&lt;/cite&gt; (via Jason Santa Maria’s article &lt;a href=&#34;http://v4.jasonsantamaria.com/articles/change-of-heart/&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Change of Heart&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Tschichold became disillusioned with sans serifs after the nazis adopted typefaces such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fonts.com/font/linotype/futura&#34;&gt;Futura&lt;/a&gt; (interestingly enough Ikea’s chosen typeface, until &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.time.com/time/business/article/0%2C8599%2C1919127%2C00.html&#34;&gt;it switched to Verdana&lt;/a&gt;). While state typeface choice might not seem particularly important, you could argue that some sans serifs reflect a desire for purity and abstract cleanliness that appeal to totalitarian systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, there’s politics in the letterforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short attention spans, mobile phones and the future of reading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/01/short-attention-spans-mobile-phones-and-the-future-of-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/01/short-attention-spans-mobile-phones-and-the-future-of-reading/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I bet you were expecting a doom filled post, rather similar to &lt;a href=&#34;http://idratherbewriting.com/2011/01/21/contemporary-reading-behaviors-favor-short-formats/&#34;&gt;this excellent, long meditation on short formats and modern reading behaviours&lt;/a&gt;. But not a word of it; reading is, I think, in rude health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact I’m willing to bet that people are reading — and writing — (whether it’s Twitter updates, Facebook pages, blogs or news stories) more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all conjecture, not science, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;The web doesn’t have the power to reduce attention spans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how could it? Where’s the cause and effect? The same attention span argument has been made &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_television#Television_sets&#34;&gt;since 1928&lt;/a&gt;, and probably before that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, people do scan and skim texts when reading from a laptop/desktop monitor. The reasons for this aren’t down to shortened attention spans, per se. Rather, it’s:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poor design&lt;/strong&gt;: laptop and desktop monitors are too wide. 16 pixel text only needs a 5-650 pixel wide column to attain a comfortable measure. What to do with the extra 450 pixels? How to fill those exciting grids? There are lots and lots of widgets out there. Adverts too. All of them next to useless for the reader who simply wants to find out something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glare&lt;/strong&gt;: anyone who works on a computer for a whole day knows how tired their eyes get. Try reading a long form article written like a Victorian novel after working in Excel for four hours to see what I mean. It’s next to impossible to read in a linear fashion, word by word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt;: if visitors are &lt;em&gt;shopping&lt;/em&gt; rather than &lt;em&gt;reading&lt;/em&gt; they’re not, unsurprisingly, reading; they’re on a mission to gather prices and information. However, if they are reading, and you serve them legible text, they’ll, well, read it. Even God (who preaches the brief missive) tells us that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.useit.com/alertbox/articles-not-blogs.html&#34;&gt;long form texts are sometimes appropriate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience at work indicates that people are willing to engage with longer texts — they’ll certainly complain if they can’t find lots of information about what we do. Sometimes, they’ll complain because they can’t be bothered to search for the information (“have you looked on the website?” — “erm, uh, yeeaahhh!”), other times because it hasn’t been organised or presented well (as Nielsen states, you should still be using headings, bolded keywords, bullets and short paragraphs, even in long form texts). However, a lot of the time it’s because the detail simply isn’t there — detail that demands a longer text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Mobile phones improve attention spans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re probably familiar with the image of a sullen teenager, disengaged from his parents (and fine literature, no doubt), staring into the eldritch light of his mobile phone. For many, this represents the end of Western civilisation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.poemhunter.com/poem/television/&#34;&gt;just as the TV did in the past&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I confidently predict that mobile devices will be good for attention spans because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design restraints will result in more readable texts; there’s nowhere to put endless widgets, adverts or even a sidebar. All the reader can focus on is the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s more comfortable reading from a mobile device than laptop or desktop monitor. You can recline, move the screen around, even take it with you from room to room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They offer more opportunities and time for reading, which is why you see iPads and Kindles on the commuter train&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some devices (e.g. Kindle) resolve the glare problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there’s no objective evidence in this (longish) article. All I can say is that I read more, and in more detail, than I did in the past, and I’ve spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time online over the last few years. And I’m also reading more of &lt;a href=&#34;http://m.guardian.co.uk/&#34;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; than ever on my humble mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>