<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Typography on Leon Paternoster </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/categories/typography/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Observer design not for us</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/07/design-observer-design-not-for-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/07/design-observer-design-not-for-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;History repeats itself quickly in the world of web design – it seems like only yesterday &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fawny.org/2009/08/12/mock-do-1/&#34;&gt;we were lambasting &lt;cite&gt;Design Observer&lt;/cite&gt; for its new–not–at–all–new design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 2014 and we&amp;#8217;re making the &lt;a href=&#34;http://typographica.org/on-typography/questions-for-the-new-design-observer/&#34;&gt;same criticisms&lt;/a&gt;: poor font choice, tiny, indistinct type, bugginess. Add some really slow loading and unresponsiveness and you have 2014&amp;#8242;s version (although to be fair the site sort of adjusts to my Nexus phone – I&amp;#8217;m guessing it sniffs rather than scales).&lt;figure class=&#34;figure aligncenter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://designobserver.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;full-bleed&#34; src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/do.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the Design Observer website&#34; width=&#34;860&#34; height=&#34;444&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Design Observer&lt;/cite&gt;: Let me count the ways&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
And yet. This website wasn&amp;#8217;t really written for me. I&amp;#8217;d go as far as to say I don&amp;#8217;t even understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who exactly is it for? Older design veterans who don&amp;#8217;t deal in the grubby functionality of fluid sized screens (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.layervault.com/comments/78785&#34;&gt;designers who aren&amp;#8217;t working class&lt;/a&gt;)? If that is the case then – actual crapness (the huge fixed header, the strange dropdown at the top of the screen etc.) aside – it may do its job well enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you dig seeing paragraphs set in Archer on screen, and like small blocks of text, and spend your day on a Mac with a large screen, &lt;cite&gt;Design Observer&lt;/cite&gt; has been &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; just for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18th century books looked like smartphones</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/06/18th-century-books-looked-like-smartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2014/06/18th-century-books-looked-like-smartphones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Liked this picture of an 18th century book &lt;cite&gt;Conjectures on Original Composition&lt;/cite&gt; by Edward Young:&lt;figure class=&#34;figure aligncenter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/small-book.gif&#34; alt=&#34;A narrow 18th century book&#34; width=&#34;399&#34; height=&#34;629&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.collisiondetection.net/mt/archives/2014/02/_thats_one_of_t.php&#34;&gt;Collision Detection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
It shows how resilient we are as readers – we can deal with any ‘difficult’ measure. Another possible similarity between now and then is the sheer &lt;em&gt;mass&lt;/em&gt; of the stuff we&amp;#8217;re publishing; a fact plenty will bemoan, but I rather like this democratic, unpretentious fecundity (he said, pretentiously…) Also chimes with &lt;a href=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/2011/01/short-attention-spans-mobile-phones-and-the-future-of-reading/&#34; title=&#34;Short attention spans, mobile phones and the future of reading&#34;&gt;something I wrote many moons ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tschichold, democratic design and the politics of typefaces</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/03/tschichold-democratic-design-and-the-politics-of-typefaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2013/03/tschichold-democratic-design-and-the-politics-of-typefaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Penguin founder Allen Lane hired Jan Tschichold to design the publisher’s book covers in 1947. Tschichold made an immediate impact:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…nothing compared to storm when Jan Tschichold arrived. Mild-mannered man with an inflexible character. Screams heard from Edinburgh to Ipswich and from Aylesbury to Bungay.” This was the result of Tschichold’s immediate effort to raise the standard of undisciplined English typesetting; to his frustration, Tschichold found himself obliged to treat the compositor not as a craftsman but as a machine, by specifying precise measurements for the spaces between each combination of letters in a title. It was the only way to get the results he desired. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/artanddesign/2008/dec/05/jan-tschichold-typography&#34;&gt;Jan Tschichold: a titan of typography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it; the Ipswich Jan Tschichold link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this is an example of what iA refer to as &lt;em&gt;Fingerspitzengefühl&lt;/em&gt;; the fine knowledge of detail that helps produce good design. (Go ahead and read &lt;a href=&#34;http://informationarchitects.net/blog/learning-to-see/&#34;&gt;Learning to See&lt;/a&gt;—you won’t be disappointed.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about design it’s very easy to adopt a reverential, exclusive tone. Design can be used as a means to up the price of a product. But it’s worth bearing in mind that many of the things we think of as examples of great design serve a democratic purpose. Tschischold invented a template for cheap, massproduced books that sold millions of copies:&lt;figure class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;full-bleed alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://leonpaternoster.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/penguin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Penguin Great Gatsby cover&#34; width=&#34;616&#34; height=&#34;887&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;secondary&#34;&gt;Tschichold&amp;#8217;s Penguin book covers, used for millions of cheaply available classics. There&amp;#8217;s no reason why the best design can&amp;#8217;t be commonplace, but it&amp;#8217;s become more and more commoditised in recent years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
Tschischold is an interesting man. He escaped the Nazis in 1933 having published &lt;cite lang=&#34;de&#34;&gt;Die neue Typographie&lt;/cite&gt;, where he claimed sans serifs were the “basic form from which the typeface of the future will grow”. By 1952 he’d performed a &lt;em&gt;volte face&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sanserif only seems to be the simpler script. It is a form that was violently reduced for little children. For adults it is more difficult to read than serifed roman type, whose serifs were never meant to be ornamental. &lt;cite&gt;On Typography&lt;/cite&gt; (via Jason Santa Maria’s article &lt;a href=&#34;http://v4.jasonsantamaria.com/articles/change-of-heart/&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Change of Heart&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Tschichold became disillusioned with sans serifs after the nazis adopted typefaces such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fonts.com/font/linotype/futura&#34;&gt;Futura&lt;/a&gt; (interestingly enough Ikea’s chosen typeface, until &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.time.com/time/business/article/0%2C8599%2C1919127%2C00.html&#34;&gt;it switched to Verdana&lt;/a&gt;). While state typeface choice might not seem particularly important, you could argue that some sans serifs reflect a desire for purity and abstract cleanliness that appeal to totalitarian systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, there’s politics in the letterforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding em or en dashes to Google docs</title>
      <link>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2011/08/adding-em-or-en-dashes-to-google-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://leonpaternoster.com.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/2011/08/adding-em-or-en-dashes-to-google-docs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Love Google docs and all that, but typographically it&amp;#8217;s a little basic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that bugs me is how it hyphenates (or rather, how it doesn&amp;#8217;t bother with hyphenation at all). There is a workaround, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s how you can add an en dash:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In an open document, open the &lt;em&gt;Tools &amp;gt; Preferences&lt;/em&gt; menu. This will display a list of characters that Google docs will replace with something else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a character (or set of characters) that you want to replace with an en dash (I chose two keyboard minus signs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the character you&amp;#8217;d like Google docs to display. Unfortunately, Google docs doesn&amp;#8217;t recognise HTML entities (e.g. &amp;#8211;); you could &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.copypastecharacter.com/&#34;&gt;find an en dash and copy it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paste your en dash into the Google docs preferences form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click OK. Google docs will now automatically replace two keyboard minus signs with an en dash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could, of course, add any other other characters via this menu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>